<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ithacan Transit Guide</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Ithacan Transit Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:32:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 19:32:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>New Cornell and Ithaca College (IC) students, faculty, and staff as well as newcomers to the Ithaca community need to know what transportation facilities in Ithaca are available to them to effectively navigate within or to or from the small, semi-isolated city, saving them time, money, and the stress of planning.&#xA;This comprehensive transportation guide aims to teach fellow Ithacans the best ways to utilize available transportation facilities by providing the available transportation facilities all in one website!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating To / From Ithaca</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/to_from_ith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:24:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/to_from_ith/</guid>
      <description>Airports Make sure to book flights at least a couple months in advance, especially if arriving near move-in dates for Cornell and Ithaca College students (August 19-25). Ithaca and Syracuse Airports are the closest options.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t have a car? Not a problem! Make sure to also check out the bus list as there are some available that drive to these airports.&#xA;Ithaca Tompkins International Airport&#xA;Closest airport for anyone in Ithaca (~15 minute drive)!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Around Ithaca</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/around_ith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 18:24:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/around_ith/</guid>
      <description>Buses If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a car, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck! There are several buses available to get around Ithaca. However, keep in mind they might not be 100% reliable when there is construction.&#xA;Tompkins Consolidated Area Transit (TCAT)&#xA;The TCAT bus system is popular amongst Cornell and Ithaca College students, faculty, and staff to get to different buildings on campus and to visit shopping centers outside of campus.&#xA;Check out this website for current bus schedules and routes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
